

# Kluchko Michael

+7 (924) 200-84-73 • <u>slidenergy@gmail.com</u> 35 years old • detailed resume with projects <u>slidenergy.github.io</u>

Expected position: Full-stack .NET developer.

#### **Professional skills**

- Back-end: .net core, C#, ASP.NET, WebApi, async programming, T-SQL, NUnit testing, Entity Framework.
- Front-end: Angular (NgRx, RxJs, TS), JS, HTML, CSS, SASS, WinForms, DevExpress, DevExtreme, Angular Material UI.
- Tools: NodeJS, JIRA, GIT, MS SQL Server.

I know **English** at the level of reading and correspondence. I have experience in **teamwork, remote** work, technical support, commercial softrware development and writing high quality and clean code for the purpose of futher support.

I have extensive experience in developing various complex **multi-user** systems from scratch, **authorization and authentication** systems. I can work with relational databases, optimize queries, tables and indexes, build an execution plan. I am able to develop **public APIs** using different approaches and technologies. I have extensive experience in **integrating various systems**. I am able to develop complex **frontend**: SPA, desktop applications. I can provide technical support, communicate with customers, clearly and consistently express my thoughts, write technical documentation. At our current place of work, we don't use message queues, microservices, React, GraphQL, Blazor, but I follow modern technologies. I am involved in the development of the project and I think in terms of tasks at the level of the entire project.

#### Work experience - 13 years

## LERS AMR Software (2017 – 2021) (www.lers.ru/soft) – Senior Full-stack .NET Developer

- I am responsible for all web development at the company, for the choice of technologies and development vectors. I set tasks and control their implementation, code review.
- I have developed a web application from scratch in Angular to replace the legacy project. The new app is a significant part of the company's core product along with the desktop and mobile app. I am promoting the idea of replacing them with a web application. I have developed an ORM-like core for server queries and caching. I implemented code-style, unit tests, reactive programming, state management, adapted the project for building a mobile application using Cordova, organized and configured the development process.
- I am participating in the development of new server functionality (.net core). I started implementing and contributed a lot to the development of the OpenApi REST API on the server.

## LERS MANAGER Company (2013 - 2017) (www.lers.ru/soft) - Middle Full-stack .NET Developer

- I participated in the development of all components of the main software complext of the company for dispatch system and metering of energy consumption, including the development of a server(.NET), database (MS SQL), client application (WinForms). Our team has created the best solution for energy accounting in the CIS counties with great potential for entering the international market.
- I have contributed a lot to the design and development of a framework for integration with other systems. I have designed and developed a public REST API, implemented the the OpenApi specification.
- I was the first to start transition into .net core and angular projects in the company. I study technologies on new and hobby projects: Unit testing, AngularJS, EntityFramework, Angular.

- I have designed and developed new product activation system by internet instead of the old offline
  one with license key verification. I accepted for support and further development a product for the
  work of the sales department with licensing of the main product. For several years I increased its
  functionality several times. I have developed a web interface for dealers and technical support.
- I have designed and developed a system for recording, storing and analyzing telemetry data: server (.net core, Entity Framework), frontend (Angular, DevExtreme). I have done deep work with optimizing SQL scripts, tables and indexes, building an execution plan, since the queries were processing large amounts of data.
- At the same time, I provided technical support to users in the CIS countries, wrote documentation, its allowed me to improve my soft-skills.

## Energy and resource saving company (2011 - 2013) - Full-stack .NET Developer

- I have developed a unique product for configuring devices and modems, its downloads by customers of competitive products exceeded the download of the main product.
- I have developed many plugins and modules for integration with other systems, a public api service, which allowed clients of other programs to switch to our product.
- I have developed a new web application for a large system from scratch (ASP.NET). The development included a completely frontend, partly a server and a database.
- I refactor the modules of the existing system, which made it possible to simplify the system itself for further development.
- All of the above actions led to several-fold increase in sales.

### Neorise LTD (2011, 6 months) - Middle Full-stack .NET Developer, freelance

- I participated in the foreign development of a car service automation system. I have developed a number of modules affecting the client application (DevExpress), server, database (MS SQL).
- I have developed a web application for scheduling mechanics tasks (WebApi, JQuery).
- I communicated with the customer at all stages of development in English.

## MPB Intersectoral information-analytical center (2009 - 2011) - Full-stack .NET Developer

- I participated in the development, maintenance of a unified medical information system and integration in all municipal healthcare institutions in Khabarovsk.
- I have written and optimized SQL queries, designed a database (MS SQL 1000 tables).
- I have designed and developed a system for creating queries for preferential medicines and integration it into Khabarovsk's healthcare institutions (.NET, DevExpress).
- I provided technical support for users of Khabarovsk healthcare institutions.

#### My projects

- I have developed a multi-user personal finance accounting system that, in automatic or manual mode imports information from banking systems (10+). It leads analytics and builds a financial report. <a href="https://github.com/slidenergy/slidfinance-backend">https://github.com/slidenergy/slidfinance-backend</a>
- I have developed a cryptocurrency trading robot based on the source codes of a distributed trading exchange. During working, I figured out how React and blockchain work.
- I mentor in my spare time and teach computer science and programming to teenagers.

#### Education - 7 years

Master degree: Informatics and computer engineering (2009-2011)

Pacific National University, Russia, Khabarovsk city

Software Engineer: Software (2004-2009)
 Khabarovsk State Technical University, Russia, Khabarovsk city